"妙警贼探" 前情提要...
Previously on White Collar...
Neal Caffrey是世界顶级的艺术品仿造家之一
Neal Caffrey's one of the world's best art forgers.
Kate在监狱里跟你说再见 然后就忙着玩消失了
Kate says adios to you in prison and gets busy with her disappearing act.
- 只差两天就见到她了  - 你这么做 可能会被再判四年
- Missed her by two days.  - Gonna give you another four years for this.
你能把我弄出去 有过先例的
You can get me out of here. There's case law, precedent.
知道这是怎么回事吗?
You understand how this works?
等于说我在你的监督下由联邦调查局看管
I've been released into FBI custody under your supervision.
那个脚铐擦伤我的腿了
This thing chafed my leg.
- 那是谁?  - 是Garrett Fowler
- Who is that?  - Garrett Fowler.
把盒子给你后 就再也不要来骚扰我和Kate
I give you the box, Kate and I never hear from you again.
- 这是我的条件  - Kate在等你
- That's my price.  - Kate's waiting for you.
如果他拿到了音乐盒会怎样?
This music box, what happens if he gets it?
我不知道 但必须要保证他拿不到
I don't know. We need to make sure he doesn't.
- 放下枪  - 放下武器
- Put your gun down.  - Drop the weapon.
- 马上把枪放下  - 放下武器
- Put the gun down, now.  - Drop the weapon.
Neal会玩失踪的 我必须要掌握他的行踪
Neal will disappear. I need to know where he is.
把磁盘给我 你想让我把这玩意儿上报给华盛顿吗?
Give me the drive. You want me to upload this to D.C?
Hudson机场 四号机库
Airstrip by the Hudson, hangar 4.
Peter啊
Peter.
飞机爆炸了
The jet exploded.
Neal Caffrey是个重犯
Neal Caffrey is a felon.
你能解释下你们的协议吗?
Will you explain the deal you had with him?
他在我的监控下服刑 期限为四年
He was serving the remainder of a four-year sentence under my supervision.
他戴着全球定位脚铐...
He was wearing an electronic monitoring anklet...
- 活动范围是两英里?  - 是的
- with a two-mile range?  - Yes.
但飞机爆炸的时候他没有戴着脚铐?
But he wasn't wearing it at the time the plane exploded?
没带
No.
你认为Caffrey先生是打算逃逸吗?
Do you believe that Mr. Caffrey was attempting to flee the country?
不会的 他已经和职业督察处达成了协议
No. He cut a deal with the Office of Professional Responsibility.
那允许他...
That allowed him...
你认为Caffrey先生想要杀害Kate Moreau吗?
Do you believe Mr. Caffrey wanted to kill Kate Moreau?
无稽之谈 肯定不会
That's ridiculous. No.
你认为有人想要把Caffrey置于死地吗?
Do you believe someone wanted Caffrey dead?
Neal是个重犯 他因伪造债券被判刑
Neal was a felon. He was convicted of bond forgery.
你可以从文件里看到...
As you can see in those files...
警察还怀疑他犯下许多其他罪行
he was suspected of doing a hell of a lot of other things.
是的 Neal是很多人的眼中钉 肉中刺
Yeah, Neal was a pain in the ass.
那么是不是有人想杀了他?
So did somebody from that past want him dead?
或许吧
Maybe.
但他也帮助我将破案率提高到93%
But he also helped me clear a 93-percent conviction rate.
这也为他树敌不少
And that makes enemies too.
但我不认为哪一点
But I don' t think any of this
和飞机爆炸有关
explains why the jet exploded.
如果想知道答案 你该去问Garrett Fowler
You want an answer to that, ask Garrett Fowler.
Fowler 你开枪打的那个职业督察处探员
Fowler, the OPR agent you shot.
他穿着防弹背心
He was wearing a vest.
- 去跟他谈  - 现在我们在跟你谈
- Talk to him.  - Right now we're talking to you.
我们不如再回顾一下发生的事
Why don't we go back over the timeline again?
怎么样?
Well?
千钧一发 没有被停职 你那有什么消息?
I'm off suspension, but hanging by a thread. What have you got?
Fowler两天前被移交到督察处 然后就没有音讯了
Fowler was handed over to OPR two days ago, then not a trace.
他们把他藏起来了 他的磁盘上有什么信息?
They're hiding him somewhere. Anything off his hard drive?
坏消息是好不容易黑进去了 数据却自动销毁了
Good and bad news. I hacked it, but the data self-corrupted.
自我蚕食病毒 好消息是什么?
A self-eating virus. What's the good news?
我修复了一条数据 是见面的时间和地点
I was able to recover one entry. A date, a time and a place.
你认为Fowler要和谁会面?
So you think Fowler set up a meeting?
这个会面是两个月后在第12街和Watershed街的交界处
He's expecting something to happen at 12th and Watershed 2 months from now.
两个月 我应该过去
Two months. I should be there.
- 我会给你安排行程  - 很开心你能回来帮我
- I'll put it on your calendar.  - Glad to have you back.
- 嘿 你去哪儿?  - 去见一个老朋友
- Hey, where you going?  - To see an old friend.
4号会面室见
Report to interview room 4.
- 怎么样?  - 他们不让我系领带
- How are you?  - They don't let me wear ties.
- 期望太高了  - 伙食依然很差
- Overrated.  - Food's as bad as I remember.
- 有咖啡吗?  - 即溶的
- Coffee?  - Instant.
还真是惨无人道啊
Cruel and unusual.
- 新西装  - 没错
- New suit.  - Heh. Yeah.
他们把警徽还给你了?
They give you your badge back?
嗯 正义的一边总会获胜
Yeah. Justice finished its inquiry.
那为什么我还在这里?
Then why am I still here?
- 他们认为是我把飞机炸了?  - 他们什么也不知道
- They think I blew up the plane?  - They don't know what to think.
- 那他们怀疑什么?  - 你试图逃逸出国
- What do they suspect?  - You were trying to escape.
逃?
Escape?
Fowler不见了
Fowler disappeared.
职业督查办不承认指导员的存在
OPR is denying mentor existed.
我有文件作证
I got paperwork that proves it did.
是啊 有人提醒我说你是最棒的伪造家
Yeah, and I've been reminded you're one of the best forgers on the planet.
听着 我们还是有可能继续合作的
Listen, there's a chance I can reinstate our deal.
- 再戴上那脚铐?  - 他们弄了一个新的
- Put the anklet back on?  - They've got a new one.
- 不会再那么磨脚  - 哇哦 听起来很不错
- Not supposed to chafe as much.  - Wow, that sounds like a great deal.
- 从一个监狱到了另一个  - 没那么夸张吧
- From one prison to another.  - Overstating that a little.
我允许你穿西装
I'll let you wear ties.
- 咖啡呢?  - 可以商量
- Coffee?  - Negotiable.
- 还有一件事 如果我们继续合作下去的话...  - 我要知道谁杀了Kate
- One thing. If we do this again...  - I have to know who killed Kate.
我会查清楚 我会告诉你的 必须查清楚
I'll find out. I'll tell you. That's how it works.
- 我能回到你那里吗?  - 你在讨价还价
- Can I get back to you?  - You're looking at three and change.
你唯一的选择就是在服刑期间为我做事 要不就在这个地方自生自灭
Your only choice is to serve out your time with me or rot in this place.
先生们 容我打断一下
I'm gonna have to interrupt this meeting, gentlemen.
被告要求与辩护律师会面
The defendant has requested the presence of his attorney.
劝劝他
Talk some sense into him.
我们会自行斟酌的 猫咪探长
We'll take that under advisement, Suit.
- 他要我劝你什么?  - Peter要我继续原来的协议
- What sense am I talking into you?  - Peter offered me my old deal.
- 戴上脚铐?  - 没错
- The anklet?  - Mm-hm.
- 想去了?  - 我不介意多个选择
- Tempted?  - I'm open to exploring my options.
我能把你弄出去 但要花不少钱
I can get you out of here, but it will cost.
- 可能会花光你的积蓄  - 我不差钱
- It will deplete most of your reserves.  - I can always get cash.
你想怎么做?
What do you wanna do?
2个月后
嗨 我是Nick 全名Nick Halden
Hi, I'm Nick. Nick Halden.
- 今天来报道  - 我们没有收到雇佣新人的通知
- Today's my first day.  - We're not expecting any new employees.
人力部的Brittany说我的员工卡和必需物品已经准备好了
Brittany in H.R. said my welcome badge and packet would be ready for me.
我没收到任何通知
Nobody told me about any of this.
等一下
Hang on.
刚刚不好意思了 你的东西在这里
I'm sorry about that. Welcome packet's right here.
嗯哼 看起来是我的
All right. Looks like me.
- 这边来 Nick  - 好的
- Come on in, Nick.  - Okay.
嗯 呃...
Yeah, just...
嗯 这里 这样?
Yeah, there. Like this?
- 我已经被解雇了吗?  - 第一天 可能有些延迟
- Am I fired already?  - First day glitches.
- 明白  - 可以了
- Gotcha.  - Here you go.
多谢
Thank you.
哦 这有个小东西 线头
Oh, you got a little something. It's lint right here.
好了 一根线头
Got it, some lint.
- 希望你能喜欢这里  - 哦 目前为止还不错
- I hope you like it here.  - Oh, so far, so good.
你不是想就这样大摇大摆地走在大街上吧
I hope you're not planning on walking with that.
没有法律禁止啊
No law against thinking about it.
- Jones  - 你好 Neal
- Jones.  - Neal.
没错 看起来都在这儿了
Yeah, it looks like it's all here.
行了 去见我们的银行分行行长吧 他们的银行可没那么安全
All right, let's go tell our branch managers their bank isn't secure.
- 走吧  - 很开心你能回来
- Let's do it.  - It's good to have you back.
回来也不错
It's good to be back.
哦 Neal
Uh, Neal.
没错
Oh, yeah.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
- 不是吧 直接踩我车上?  - 拜托 只不过踩一下
- Right on the car?  - Oh, come on. It's just a shoe.
--=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
妙警贼探 第二季第1集
--=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=--
协调: Tracy
翻译: 落寞卷菜% 西皮jo 初见 伊娃
校对: Tracy 影子
早上好各位
Morning, gentlemen.
市中心的互惠银行有着相似的布局 用着相同的安全系统
All midtown mutual banks have similar layouts and use the same security system.
- Renee Simmons小姐  - 先生们
- Miss Renee Simmons  - Gentlemen.
负责你们分行的安全工作...
Who's in charge of security for your branches...
她要求我们针对分行的安全性做个测试
requested that we conduct a test on that security.
您能解释一下原因吗?
Would you please tell us why this is necessary?
我们发现了一些漏洞
We found several flaws.
嗨
Hi.
嗯 唔 嗯 很多钱
Mm-mm-mm. That's a lot of money.
在地下室我通过了金属检测仪的检测
Basement access let me bypass the metal detectors at the entrances.
出纳箱有系统保护 但你们的员工需要提高警惕性
Teller cages are protected, but your employees need to be vigilant.
员工要把员工卡带在脖子上
Staff should wear badges around their neck.
别在腰间很容易被顺手牵羊
Clipped to their waist, too easy to lift.
你们正在使用的染色包很容易被识别出来
The old dye packs you're using are too easy to spot.
而且密码应该每天更换 而不是一周更换一次
And, guys, the passcodes need to change daily, not weekly.
你们每个人在上周都收到了一张这样的卡...
Each of you have received a card like this in the past week...
这个人自称"建筑师"
from someone calling himself the Architect.
我们相信在达拉斯 芝加哥和波士顿抢劫银行的 跟他是同一个人
We believe this is the same person who has hit banks in Dallas, Chicago and Boston.
如果他继续用同样的方式作案...
If he's operating under the same MO...
一周之内 你们中就会有银行金库被抢
one of your vaults will be emptied within a week.
这就是原因 那么让我们来拟定计划吧
That's why it's necessary. So let's strategize.
进行得很顺利嘛
That went great.
我想他们今晚肯定睡得很香
I'm sure they'll sleep soundly tonight.
那么他们开始紧张的时候 我该怎么安慰他们?
So, what do I tell them when they start to panic?
告诉他们 我们会保证他们的系统安全 而且联邦调查局也会帮忙
Tell them that we're shoring up their security and that the bureau is on it.
这在达拉斯 芝加哥和波士顿有用吗?
Did that help in Dallas, Chicago and Boston?
这是在纽约 我们一定能抓住他
This is New York. We'll catch him.
希望吧
I hope so.
"我们一定能抓住他" 只说了半截吧?
"We'll catch him." Your halftime speech?
- 你本该说些什么的  - 那个家伙太狡猾了 好吗?
- You could've said something.  - This guy is amazing, all right?
- 达拉斯那单就干得不错 芝加哥那单 简直就是件艺术品  - 波士顿呢?
- Dallas was good, Chicago, a work of art.  - Boston?
- 我至今没弄明白他是怎么做到的  - 真的?
- I still don't know how he did Boston.  - Really?
那我们最好尽快查明 我可不想让曼哈顿也遭洗劫
Well, we better figure out how, because I do not want to add Manhattan to that list.
- 你还好吗?  - 是的 是的 我还好
- You holding up?  - Yeah. Yeah, I'm holding up.
- 你确定?  - 嗯
- You sure?  - Yeah.
我要... 嗯 呃
I'm gonna... Mm-hm.
你在哪儿?
Where are you?
我们定了协议
We agreed on a protocol.
你用了变声器?
Are you using a voice changer?
在长椅上坐下 打开时代杂志 翻到国际板块
You sit on the bench, open the Times to the international section.
- 按照约定来  - 你用了变声器
- That's what we agreed on.  - You're using a voice changer.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
- 我没看见你翻开报纸  - 赶紧过来
- I don't see a newspaper open.  - Get over here.
你负全责哦 猫咪探长
It's your dime, Suit.
- Neal怎么样?  - 你跟他呆的时间不比我少
- How's Neal doing?  - You spend as much time with him as I do.
我需要他 我可全指望他了 很多人都指望着他
I need him. I am counting on him. A lot of people are counting on him.
他可不能出什么问题
And I don't need him going section eight on me.
得给他点时间
He's not exactly forthcoming.
Kate才死了两个月 谁能恢复得那么快
Kate's only been dead two months. No one can snap back that fast.
你的意思是 你俩都没有调查机场发生了什么?
Are you telling me the two of you aren't looking into what happened at that airport?
你该问问 "他怎么样了?"
The question was, "How's he doing?"
- 而不是"他在干什么?"  - 行 那你怎么想?
- Not, "What is he doing?"  - All right, then what do you think?
交换条件
Quid pro quo.
好吧 他有时会发抖
All right. He's got the shakes.
他脑海里回想之前发生的事 他就会害怕
He's flashing back to that moment in his mind and he's freaking out about it.
到你说了
Your turn.
依你所想 他还是会有些好奇是谁杀了Kate
As you may imagine, he's a little curious as to who may have killed Kate.
他是不是觉得杀Kate的人实际上也想杀了他?
Does he think whoever killed her was trying to kill him?
他这样想过
It's crossed his mind.
好吧 我会一直盯着我这边的情况
All right, I'll keep looking into things on my side.
在我发信息给你之前 让他一直忙着
Until you hear from me, let's keep him busy.
现在我们接了个复杂的案子 就让他负责这个
We've got a good case now. Let's keep him working on that.
- 我怎么做?  - 你是他朋友 你会有办法的
- How do I do that?  - You're his friend. You'll figure it out.
你离开这里后 所有东西原封未动
I kept everything as you left it.
- 我看还真和我离开时候一样  - 欢迎回来
- Exactly as I left it, I see.  - Oh, welcome back.
一想到你待在汽车旅馆 我就接受不了了
I couldn't bear the thought of you at that motel.
另外 你都不想象不到你不在的时候这里是多安静
Besides, you can't imagine how quiet it is around here without you.
- 我时不时喜欢来点刺激的事  - 我也是
- I like a little, uh, excitement now and then.  - Me too.
- 谢谢你 June  - 不客气
- Thank you, June.  - Of course.
快来看
Let's see it.
- 有不少资料  - 我知道
- There's a lot.  - I know.
资料都在这了吗?
This is everything?
是 这是你查到的关于Kate 还有Fowler和指导员的所有资料
Yeah. Everything on your search for Kate, Fowler, Mentor.
- 你有Alex的消息吗?  - 没
- You heard from Alex?  - No.
自从那次爆炸之后 她一直很低调 别怪她
Since the explosion, she's been laying low. Can't blame her.
她会出现的
She'll surface.
那音乐盒呢?
What about the music box?
- 根据记录 新来的猫咪女探员...  - 那是Diana
- According to the log, the new lady Suit...  - That would be Diana.
自从Peter从Fowler手中拿回音乐盒...
Diana logged it into evidence in your New York office...
Diana就把它放在了纽约办公室的证物处
after Peter recovered it from Fowler.
我看看它是不是在那里 那些炸飞机的人就是想要那个盒子
I wanna see if it's there. Whoever blew up the plane wants that box.
他们不会就此善罢甘休
They're not gonna let it sit in an evidence locker collecting dust.
我只要找到那个想要这个盒子的人 也就找到了杀害Kate的凶手
We find the person who wants the box, we find who killed Kate.
"建筑师" 是个响亮的绰号
The Architect. That's an excellent sobriquet.
- 是你回来的第一个案子吗?  - 是啊
- Is this your first case back?  - Yeah.
- 我想要个新昵称  - Mozzie不够响亮了吗?
- I need a new Nickname.  - Mozzie's not cutting it anymore?
叫"提问人"? 或者"怀疑者"?
What about, um, the Question? Or perhaps the Skeptic?
大忽悠?
Conman?
- 这个"建筑师"是个银行抢劫犯吗?  - 还很厉害
- The Architect, he's a bank robber?  - A good one.
你什么时候开始关心联邦调查局的案子了?
Since when are you concerned with FBI cases?
从你开始为警察做事开始
Uh, since you started spiraling into the dark place.
也许你还记得 在过去的日子里我曾与银行劫匪勾结在一起
And as you may remember, I have colluded on a bank heist or two in my day.
说说 我们都知道什么?
Come on. What do we got?
好吧 5年里干净利落地做了3件劫案 没留下踪迹和任何证据
All right. Three clean jobs in five years. No trail, no evidence.
我们就只有这些业务名片
All we have are these business cards.
是浮雕版的 经典
Embossed. Very classy.
这个A是什么? 我不知道这是什么字体
What do make of the A? I don't recognize the typeface.
鉴证科也查不出来
Forensics doesn't either.
这个是自定义字体 体现了他的狂妄自大
Custom font. That speaks to a high degree of hubris.
嗯
Mm-hm.
你怎么想?
What do you think?
字体细长倾斜 肯定是受西里尔字体影响
The elongated slant, it could be a Cyrillic influence.
有点俄罗斯字体 嗯
A bit of Russian. Mm-hm.
如果是你留名片 你怎么写呢?
If you left a calling card, how'd you sign it?
我从不留名片 那太无耻了 你会那么做吗?
I'd never leave a card. It's way too brazen. Would you?
你当然会
Of course you would.
更好的问题应该是 如果你是他 你会留什么样的名片?
The better question is, if you were him, what card would you leave?
- 早上好  - 在名片上找到些线索
- Morning.  - Found something on the card.
我想模糊派俄国画家大概有1000个吧
I'll take obscure Russian painters for 1000.
这字母A一定是受西里尔字体的影响
The A has a definite cyrillic influence.
我们的技术人员已经破解了这个
Well, our tech guys already cracked that one.
如果"建筑师"是个疯狂的俄罗斯人 那也不能排除我们名单上的其他嫌疑人
If the Architect is a Mad Russian, that doesn't narrow down our list of possibles.
这人不是俄罗斯人 但很迷俄国画
Not a Russian, but a fan of Russian painting.
Ivan Aivazovsky 看他的签名
Ivan Aivazovsky. Look at his signature.
看看啊
Oh, look at that.
有了
Got it.
看你俩一起工作 合作很愉快嘛
Look at you two working together, look at that teamwork.
我们对每一个拍卖会进行挖掘分析 看是谁拍下Aivazovskys的画
We dug up every auction to see who's been bidding on Aivazovskys.
太好了 人不少啊
Excellent. That's a pretty thick list.
如果我们再对照这份名单和在达拉斯 芝加哥生意业务的联系...
What if we cross-reference people with a business connection in Dallas, Chicago...?
就这
Right here.
- 这样 名单简短了  - 就一个名字
- Yeah, the list gets shorter.  - One name.
叫Edward Walker
Edward Walker.
我们这就去拜访他一下 走吧
Let's go have a visit. Let's do it.
干得漂亮 干得棒极了
Good work. Good work.
Walker先生 这两位先生说他们是联邦调查局的
Mr Walker, these gentlemen are with the FBI.
如果你因为我把球打进哈得孙河里给我开单子 我就给你张支票
If you're here to give me a ticket for hitting balls into the Hudson, I'll write you a check.
- Whitney 拿我的支票簿来  - 我们不开罚单
- Whitney, get me my checkbook.  - The Bureau doesn't give tickets.
这种情况 Whitney 拿我的高尔夫准许证来 好吗?
Well, in that case, Whitney, get my golf permit, will you?
我是特别探员Peter Burke 这是我的顾问Neal Caffrey
I'm special agent Peter Burke. This is my consultant, Neal Caffrey.
Caffrey先生 你主要负责什么方面顾问?
What do you consult on, Mr Caffrey?
关于专长领域的调查
Investigations that involve my areas of expertise.
- 都有什么领域?  - 那太多了
- What areas are those?  - It's a long list.
- 来 试试打一球  - 不 谢了
- Here, try a swing.  - No, thanks.
你最后一次把高尔夫球打出世界的顶端是什么时候?
Oh, when was the last time you got a chance to hit a golf ball off the top of the world?
好吧
Oh, okay.
- 你认得这个吗?  - 我可不是什么"建筑师"
- You recognize this?  - Oh, I'm not an Architect.
确实不是 但你的确有着大把时间去搞套利基金
No, you're just a hedge fund manager with too much time on his hands.
- 有个爱好不犯罪吧?  - 那要看是什么爱好了
- Well, having a hobby is not illegal, is it?  - Depends on the hobby.
Burke探员 有什么我能帮到你的吗?
Is there something specific I can help you with, Agent Burke?
现代俄罗斯艺术 你有Aivazovskys的画吗?
Contemporary Russian art. Got any Aivazovskys?
有3幅 你是不是想偷一幅?
Three. You thinking about stealing one?
根据你脚踝上那个装置
It's that device on your ankle.
联邦调查局一直密切监视你 你之前肯定犯过事
You must have been some kind of criminal for the FBI to wanna keep you so close.
确实
I was.
喔 你把球打到切希尔码头了
Ooh, you sliced that one over into the Chelsea Pier.
要知道 那可不在我的打球许可范围里
You know, my permit doesn't cover that.
我了解到你在达拉斯 芝加哥 还有波士顿设了办公处
I understand you have offices in Dallas, Chicago and Boston.
我在全世界很多大城市设立了办公室
I have offices in most major cities around the world.
能告诉我去年4月19日你在哪里吗?
Could you tell me where you were on April 19th of last year?
让我想出来? 我都不记得了
Off the top of my head? I have no idea.
但我助理可以帮我查一下 Whitney有我的日程表
But my assistant could look it up for me. Whitney keeps my calendar.
4月19日吗?
Uh, April 19th?
当然 我很清楚我当时在哪里 我也很高兴告诉你...
Oh, of course, I know exactly where I was and I would be happy to tell you...
鉴于你通过胡乱猜测我 一个匿名卡片和乱七八糟关于俄国艺术的问题
Providing you can get a warrant based on some bizarre connection you've made...
之间的联系 你就可以拿到搜查令
between me, an anonymous card and random questions about Russian art.
现在很抱歉
Now, if you'll excuse me.
我手头还有好多事情要处理 Whitney会带你们出去
I, uh, have too much time on my hands. Whitney can show you out.
哦 Caffrey先生 我建议你下次犯事的时候
Oh, and Mr. Caffrey, a suggestion for the next time you commit a crime.
别被抓住
Don't get caught.
向后挥杆前 你得动作娴熟
And on your backswing, just keep it smooth.
啊
Ah.
- Walker让你很不爽吗?  - 没有
- Did Walker get to you?  - Nope.
但我真希望是他干的 抓他会挺有趣的
But I hope he did it. Be fun to arrest him.
- 他就是让你不爽了 别干傻事  - 我不会的
- He got to you. Don't do anything stupid.  - I won't.
别告诉我一点可能性也没有 这里有千万只眼睛盯着我们
Don't tell me it's not a possibility. We are under a ton of scrutiny here.
- 我们两个都是  - 明白
- Both of us.  - Got it.
为什么他这样的人会那样做? 他又不缺钱
So why would somebody like him do it? He doesn't need the money.
那家伙在摩天大楼上打高尔夫 你说得没错 他真无聊
Guy's chipping golf balls off skyscrapers. You said it. He's bored.
所以他是为了一时痛快冒险犯罪吗?
So he's gonna risk prison for an adrenaline rush?
- 是  - 嗯
- Yeah.  - Hmm.
听着 我要回办公室 然后和El一起吃饭
Listen, I'm gonna head back to the office and grab a late bite with El.
- 今天就到这里  - 替我向Elizabeth问好
- We're done for the day.  - Tell Elizabeth I say hi.
- Neal 别犯傻  - 不会犯傻的
- Neal, nothing stupid.  - Nothing stupid.
联系航空局 我们需要飞机航班记录 包括商用机和私人机
Talk to the FAA. We need flight records, commercial and private.
查一下Walker之前是不是在达拉斯 芝加哥或者波士顿...
Wanna know if Walker was in Dallas, Chicago or Boston...
- 就抢劫的那段时间  - 好的
- the dates of the robberies.  - Done.
我会查一下信用卡 电话记录 可能查到他打过电话...
I'll run credit cards, phone records. Maybe get him making a call...
- 或者入住什么宾馆  - 谢了 有结果了告诉我
- or place him at a hotel.  - Thank you. Let me know what you find.
我查了你的工作日程
I checked your calendar.
Fowler的秘密会议是在三天后 这就是会议地点?
Fowler's mystery meeting is in three days. These are the locations?
人少 没有监控摄像 几个巷口
Very little foot traffic, no cameras, several alley exit points.
- 我明白Fowler选这个地方的原因了  - 我会去的
- I see why Fowler picked it.  - I'm gonna be there.
我们都该去
We both should be.
哦 对不起 天啊
Ooh! Oh, sorry. Oh, god.
- 过道太窄了...  - 嗨
- These tables are so close...  - Hey.
- Whitney  - Caffrey先生?
- Whitney.  - Mr Caffrey?
- 叫我Neal吧  - 好
- Please, Neal, Neal.  - Great.
这就是我喜欢纽约的原因 到处都能遇见熟人
That's what I love about New York. Small world.
请坐 要不要一起?
Please, sit down. Join me?
- 可以吗?  - 请坐
- Sure?  - Please, sit down.
鳕鱼角 能遇到之前去过汉普顿的人真好
Cape cod? What a relief to meet someone else who's over the Hamptons.
就是 我总觉得我沉浸在菲茨杰拉德的小说中
I know. I always felt like I was in a Fitzgerald novel.
或者是因为我不是纽约人
Maybe it's because I'm not from New York.
咱俩真是一样
Kindred ex-patriot.
要不要再喝一杯?
Would you like another glass of wine?
好啊 一起喝一杯
Yeah, let's.
- 这环境真好  - 是挺好
- You know, this is nice.  - It is nice.
- 在这 环境美得你都忘了你的眼前人  - 是 没错
- Live here, you forget what's in front of you.  - Yeah. Ha, ha.
- Neal最近怎样?  - 挺好
- How's Neal doing?  - Great.
- 他是那么说的  - 他一直在装没事 是吧?
- As far as he says.  - He's putting up a facade, huh?
他肯定会 这是他的本性
Of course he is. It's his natural state.
问题就在于我不知道有多糟糕
Problem is I don't know how bad it is.
你怎么想的?
What do you think?
我想他心灵肯定受到重创
Think he went through one hell of a trauma.
我还在想他有没有做好准备面对...
I also think if he was ready for a straitjacket...
然后笑着对我说 "Peter 你要相信我 "
he'd be grinning and saying, "Peter, you have to trust me."
他要做回自己还需要些时日
Well, it's gonna take him some time to become himself again.
所以比起马撒葡萄园岛 你更喜欢楠塔基特?
So you are prefer nantucket over martha's vineyard?
- 对啊 个人喜好  - 绝对的
- Yeah, it's a sentimental thing.  - Absolutely.
- 说说国外的  - 无疑是马尔代夫
- Let's go international.  - Oh, Maldives, hands down.
那蓝绿色的海水真是美轮美奂
Those turquoise waters are unreal.
- 这个答案还行吧?  - 很棒啊
- That an acceptable answer?  - Very good.
- 我喜欢塞舌尔  - 是吗?
- Mine's the Seychelles.  - Yeah?
- 你知道那里的沙滩真是粉色的吗?  - 哇
- You know the sand's actually pink?  - Wow.
是 真的是粉色的
Yeah, it's actually pink.
哇
Wow.
我再去给你叫一杯 但等我回来 给我说说欧洲城市
I'm gonna get you another drink, but when I come back, European cities.
不能说巴塞罗那哦
And you are not allowed to say Barcelona.
- 喔  - 等我
- Ooh.  - Ha-ha-ha.
- 他知道吗?  - 还不知道有多严重
- Does he know?  - Not how bad it is.
他知道我们被当局严密监控
Well, he knows that we're under enhanced scrutiny by the Bureau.
但他不知道如果我们把案子搞砸了 我就要失业了...
What he doesn't know is if we drop a case, I'm collecting unemployment...
他只能变卖麦考利・库尔金的画换钱了
and he's using pictures of Macaulay Culkin for money.
就在飞机爆炸之前
There was this moment right before the plane exploded.
Neal正要离开
Neal was walking away from me.
他停住了 转头想要说些什么
He stopped and he turned around and he was about to say something.
然后...
Then...
- 你觉得他要说什么?  - 不知道
- What do you think he was gonna say?  - I don't know.
- 你觉得他会留下来吗?  - 抛下Kate?
- Do you think he was gonna stay?  - And leave Kate?
- 我不知道 反正不重要了  - 我觉得这很重要
- I don't know. Doesn't matter.  - Well, I think it matters.
为什么? 反正也无从得知了
Why? It's kind of a moot point now.
对你很重要
It matters to you.
手机卡复制好了
Copied her SIM card.
可惜你在利用她 人家挺不错的
Too bad you're conning this one. She's cute.
我知道
Yeah, I noticed.
- 现在残酷是为了她好  - 说得对
- Be cruel to be kind.  - You're right.
真相伤人啊 Mozz
Truth hurts, Mozz.
我想给你看几张在摩洛哥拍的照片 在我手机里
I have gotta show you these photos from Morocco. They're in my phone.
- 应该在我巨大的包包里  - 是不是放桌上了
- Which is in my giant handbag somewhere.  - Maybe it's on the table.
- 我总是随手把东西放在眼前  - 有可能
- I always leave my stuff right in front of me.  - Could be, you know.
不 就是在包里
No, it's in here.
- 找到了  - 好吧
- Here it is.  - There you go.
呃...
Um...
你想不想去我家一起看照片?
You know, do you wanna look at these back at my place?
- 你家在哪?  - 格拉梅西公园
- Where's that?  - Gramercy Park.
- 好的 在我的活动范围之内  - 什么?
- Yeah, that's within my radius.  - Your what?
哦 嗯...
Oh, um...
- 那是定位脚铐吗?  - 准确的说是电子监控脚铐
- Is that a tracking anklet?  - Electronic monitoring anklet actually.
说来有趣呢
It's a funny story though.
几年前 因为盗窃和伪造艺术品 联邦调查局追捕我
A couple years ago, Feds came after me for everything from art theft to counterfeiting.
但他们只抓到了我伪造证券的把柄
They only got me on bond forgery.
- 我还以为你在联邦调查局工作  - 没错 跟Peter一起工作
- I thought you worked for the FBI.  - Oh, yeah, yeah, with Peter.
就是他抓住了我 两次呢
He caught me. Both times.
不管怎么说 今天是个好日子
Anyway, this is a big day for me.
我出狱以来 你是第一个跟我喝酒的女孩子
You're the first girl I've had a drink with since I got out of prison.
- 哇  - 没什么问题 对吧? 还是...?
- Wow.  - That's not a problem, is it? Or...?
我得走了
I should really go.
好吧 因为我说的? 你...?
Okay. Is it something I said? Are you...?
你知道怎么联系我 过得愉快
You know where to find me. Ha, ha. Have a good one.
假释期的Neal Caffrey 不太妙啊
Neal Caffrey on paper, not so great.
还有很多手续要办
It's a lot to process.
- 至少我们拿到了Walker的日程表  - 有什么发现吗?
- Well, at least we got Walker's calendar.  - Anything?
以往每次银行劫案发生前几天 他的日程表都标注成绿色
On the days of the previous bank heists, his itinerary is highlighted in green.
- 其他的日子是蓝色的  - 绿色代表钞票
- Usually it's blue.  - Green for money.
是吗? 象征手法我都生疏了
Oh, really? The symbolism had escaped me.
- 看看他明天的日程  - 中午在第一联合银行开会
- Look at tomorrow.  - Got a meeting at First Unity Bank at noon.
标注成绿色
Marked in green.
看来我们要抓住他了
I think we got him.
你碰巧遇到了她 然后她请你喝了一杯?
You happened to run into her and then she invited you for a drink?
我就爱纽约这一点
Gotta love New York.
是啊 然后她给了你手机卡的副本
Yeah, and then she handed you a copy of her SIM card.
我是个秘密线人 对吧?
I'm a confidential informant, right?
如果换成别人打探到这个消息 然后告诉你 你眼睛都不会眨一下就接受了
If someone found this on the street and brought it to you, you wouldn't blink.
我跟你说过 别做傻事
I told you, nothing stupid.
有消息说 明天中午Walker要对第一联合银行下手
Word on the street is that Walker's gonna hit the First Unity Branch tomorrow at noon.
- 你肯定吗?  - 是的
- You're sure about this?  - Oh, yeah.
全体人员准备就绪
We've got everybody in position.
- 你怎么肯定这家银行会被抢?  - 我们收到消息了
- What makes you sure this is the target?  - Word on the street.
我不明白 你为什么觉得这家银行不够安全?
I don't understand. Why don't you think this bank's secure?
他们还没来得及安装我们推荐的那些安全系统
They haven't had time to install the security we recommended.
- 你进去过?  - 还出来了
- Been inside?  - I'm very thorough.
我们重置了所有的金库门 现在密码每天一换
Well, we've reset the vault doors in all of our locations to change daily.
没有通行密码不可能进去
No way they're getting in there without the access codes.
他们可不是省油的灯
These guys have bravado.
达拉斯银行早上9点被抢 芝加哥银行在午饭时间被抢
Dallas was hit at 9 a.m. Chicago, at the lunch hour.
- 怎么回事?  - 西北门警卫中午去吃饭了
- What?  - The northwest guard takes lunch at noon.
- 这就是他们的突破口  - 第一小组就绪
- That's their point of entry.  - Team One is clear.
金库楼梯 安全
Vault stairwell, clear.
- 怎么回事?  - 声控警报器被触发了
- What do we got?  - Sound-activated alarm was triggered.
情况不明 正向金库移动
I got no visual. Accessing vault.
- 有可疑分子吗?  - 下面一个人都没有
- Do you see anyone?  - Nobody down here.
也许他们破坏了摄像头 逃过了监控
They could've disabled the detectors, bypassed those cameras.
全体行动 查出是什么触发了警报
All units go. Find out what triggered that alarm.
我们正在进入
We're moving in.
快上 快上 金库里有情况
Move it, move it. We got something inside the vault.
你肯定不会相信 在外面等我
You're not gonna believe this. Meet me outside.
Jones 看着监控
Jones, take the monitor.
- 怎么回事?  - 这是你们的演习训练吗?
- What's going on?  - This one of your bank tests?
- 什么意思?  - 这个放在其中的一个保险箱里
- What do you mean?  - That was inside a safety-deposit box.
- 谁的保险箱?  - Peter Burke的
- Whose name was on the box?  - Peter Burke.
有人在耍你呢 Burke 以后别再浪费我的时间了
Someone's messing with you, Burke. In the future, don't waste my time.
也别浪费我手下的时间
Don't waste my men's time.
看啊 这不是Burke探员和他的私人犯罪顾问吗
Well, well, well, if it isn't Agent Burke and his personal criminal consultant.
真是缘分啊
What a coincidence.
- 没想到你会来这 Walker  - 为什么?
- Odd seeing you here, Walker.  - Why is that?
我在街对面的尼克斯大厦开会
I have a meeting right across the street at Nix Towers.
好像我们错过了好戏 闹钟不错
I guess we missed all the excitement. Nice clock.
先生们 走吧
Gentlemen.
- 他耍了我 Peter  - 嗯
- He played me, Peter.  - Yeah.
现在我们有麻烦了
Now we got problems.
- 他们已经进去快一个小时了  - 嗯
- They've been in there for almost an hour.  - Yeah.
- 你说他们会让我们继续查吗?  - 跟司法部打交道 只丢了案子就算幸运的了
- You think we'll lose the case?  - With the Department of Justice, we'll be lucky if that's all that happens.
- 别这样 我们是被算计了 他们知道  - 他们觉得Peter应该知道
- Come on. We were set up. They know that.  - They think Peter should've known that.
这里是联邦调查局 Neal 没有把握 我们不会行动的
This is the FBI, Neal. We don't act unless we're sure.
Peter就是信了你
Peter trusted your lead.
- 今天不太顺  - 你说呢?
- So today was a bit of a setback.  - You think?
真是奇耻大辱
Took me a while to wipe the egg off of my face.
- 我们会抓住他的  - 他已经不归我们管了
- We can catch this guy.  - This guy is no longer our investigation.
真糟糕
This is bad.
有件事我想告诉你
There's something you should know.
那天在机场...
When we were at the hangar that day...
在那些发生之前 我本打算告诉你件事
before everything happened, I was gonna tell you something.
什么事?
What?
我不想再逃了
I didn't wanna run anymore.
如果我登上飞机 不管我得到了什么...
If I had gotten on that plane, regardless of whatever deal was made...
- 都不是真正的自由  - 为什么?
- it wouldn't have felt like freedom.  - Why?
因为那是在逃跑
Because it was an escape.
你说得对 Peter 我的生活在这里
You're right, Peter. I have a life here.
如果当时你能救Kate的话...
If there was something you could've done to protect Kate...
- 你一定会救的  - 我会的
- you would've.  - I would've.
就像我相信你能抓到Walker一样
The same way I know you can get Walker.
- 被坏蛋耍了很不爽 是吧?  - 特别是让自己的朋友看起来像白痴一样
- Not fun being tweaked by bad guys, is it?  - When your friend looks like an idiot.
- 你说什么?  - 不是说你... 你没有...
- What?  - Not that you... you didn't look...
- 就一小点  - 你只是... 好吧
- Little bit, yeah.  - You kind of... yeah.
好了 我们从头理一遍
All right, let's start from the top.
他为什么要送卡片去警告银行?
Why would he send a card to warn the bank?
- 向我们挑衅?  - 为什么要这么做?
- To challenge us?  - For what purpose?
看我们是不是他的对手 是个试验
To see if we're on his level. It's a test.
没有旗鼓相当的对手 游戏就没意思了
No fun playing unless you have a worthy opponent.
他想看看我们够不够格
He wants to see if we're as good as he is.
- 停一下  - 怎么了?
- Go back.  - What?
- 你说他在试我们  - 看看我们会怎么做
- You said test.  - To see what we'd do.
- 我们怎么做的?  - 我们测试了...
- What did we do?  - We ran the...
我们测试了安保系统
We ran the security.
我们帮他找到了安保的破绽
We revealed the bank's weaknesses to him.
我想知道抢劫案发生前局里有没有测试城里其他银行的安保系统
I wonder if the bureau had security tests on the other cities' banks before the robberies.
- 你打给谁?  - Jones
- Who are you calling?  - Jones.
说曹操 曹操就打电话来了 Jones 正想打给你
Oh, look at that, ESP. Jones, I was just calling you.
Peter 打开电视
Peter, turn on your TV.
- 怎么了?  - 三频道
- Why?  - Channel 3.
全市所有银行的36个警报系统全部被触发
City officals are reporting a total of thirty-six alarms have gone off in banks throughout the city.
- 情况十分危急...  - 全市的警察肯定都出动了
- There's serious speculation...  - Every cop in the city must be out there right now.
- 纽约警察局的电话没人接  - 他把我们都牵制住了
- I can't get anybody from N.Y.P.D.  - He's spreading us thin.
- 这又是调虎离山之计  - 那些银行并没有Walker的卡片
- It's another misdirect.  - None of these banks got Walker's cards.
- 他还是会对开始的五家银行之一下手  - 说得没错
- He's going after one of the initial five.  - You got that right.
- Renee说她重置了金库密码  - 如果没有她 谁也进不去
- Renee said she changed the vault access codes.  - No one can get in without her.
我们得抢在他们之前找到她
We gotta find her before someone else does.
请保持通讯线路通畅
Keep the lines of communication open.
- 晚上愉快  - 你也是
- Have a good night.  - You too.
不好意思 先生们 我们要下班了
I'm sorry, gentlemen. We're closed for the night.
请离开吧
You'll have to go now.
别急着走 女士 我们需要留条退路
Not so fast, lady. We need to make a withdrawal.
别动手
Get your hands off me.
- 放开我  - 闭嘴 把门锁上
- Let go of me.  - Shut up. Lock those doors.
- 快到第一联合银行了  - 就是在那里我们找到的闹钟
- Almost at First Unity.  - First Unity, where we arrested the clock.
那里的警报系统又被触发了 城里的银行有可能被抢劫
Their alarms are going off again. Banks in town are being robbed.
- 我觉得不是  - 你觉得这是个烟雾弹?
- I don't think so.  - Think it's a smokescreen?
嗯 Neal和我正在赶往中心互助银行
Yup. Neal and I are headed to Midtown Mutual.
- 互助银行是少数几个没有动静的银行之一  - 没错
- Midtown's one of the few that's silent.  - Exactly.
如果Walker的同伙在那里 你们单独行动太危险了
If Walker's crew are there, can't go without backup.
那就给我们派点增援 我有预感他们在找Renne
Then get us some. I got a feeling they're going after Renee.
- 好的 我会派特种部队过去  - 快走
- Okay, I'll find you a SWAT team.  - Let's go. Move it.
- 看到他们了吗?  - 嗯 看到了
- You see them?  - Yeah, I did.
- 你要去哪?  - 得找个突破口
- Where you going?  - Gotta break in.
- 谁告诉你进去的  - 就算我们能进这道门... 我们也进不去吧
- Nobody said anything about breaking in.  - Even if we could get through these doors... which we can't...
- 进去了也会被他们发现的 所以得另找门路  - 没有其他门路
- They'd see us. Go another way.  - There's no other way.
- 自从你测试了他们的系统之后 地下室就被封了  - 地下室只是最简单的进入方法
- We sealed off the basement after your test.  - The basement was the easiest way in.
- 最简单的?  - 还有别的方法的
- Easiest?  - There's always another way.
来吧 Peter
Come on, Peter.
- 看来Walker知道屋顶的通风口  - 嗯
- Looks like Walker knew about the roof vent.  - Yeah.
- 他有无线通讯设备  - 我们得速战速决
- He's got a radio.  - We're gonna have to do this quickly.
不能让他通知其他人
Before he alerts the rest of them.
联邦调查局 放下武器...
FBI. Drop your weap...
看来不能活捉了 警长
So much for taking them alive, sheriff.
- 他要告诉Walker我们在这里了  - 不会的
- Now he's gonna tell Walker we're up here.  - No, he's not.
立刻 放下武器...
Now, drop your weap...
- 放他走吧  - 我们得快点找到Renee
- Let him go.  - We gotta get to Renee.
- 枪法不错 Butch  - 谢谢 Sundance(著名腐剧"虎豹小霸王"里的角色)
- Good shooting, Butch.  - Thanks, Sundance.
好了 一 二 三
All right, one, two, three.
怎么样? 准备好闯入银行了吗?
What do you say? Ready to break into a bank?
你打算什么时候把你那些秘密通道都告诉我?
Were you ever gonna share your alternate access route with me?
不刚告诉你了嘛
I just did.
承认吧 Peter 我们是最佳拍档
Admit it, Peter. We'd make a pretty decent team.
- 抢银行的?  - 我看到你笑了
- Bank robbers?  - I see you smiling.
声名狼藉的Caffrey和Burke 我们会被传为佳话的
Come on, the infamous Caffrey and Burke. We'd be legends.
- 我都能想象出通缉令的样子  - 那也是先Burke后Caffrey
- I can see the wanted posters.  - It'd be Burke and Caffrey.
快走
Okay, move.
好了 撤退吧 同志们
All right, stand down, guys. Pack it up.
- 又是闹钟?  - 他们在城里的银行里都放上了闹钟
- More clocks?  - They're setting alarms off all over the city.
那你现在肯听我的了吧? 我们得尽快赶到中心互助银行
Now will you listen to me? We've gotta get to Midtown Mutual.
- 门卡本该还给银行的  - 幸好我没还吧?
- That was supposed to be returned to the bank.  - You glad it wasn't?
这边 这边
This way, this way.
- 打开金库  - 我在努力试了
- Open the vault.  - I'm trying. I'm doing my best.
- 那是Walker吗?  - 我认不出
- Is it Walker?  - I can't tell.
我在试了 不太记得
I'm trying. I don't remember.
有四人 都有枪 和Renee在金库里
Four of them, armed, in the vault with Renee.
把她带走 把她绑在办公室 绑紧点
Take her, put her in her office. Don't be stingy with the tape.
他们往回走呢
They're coming back.
楼梯下有个紧急出口 你分散他们注意力 我带她去逃出去?
There's an emergency exit off the staircase. Create the distraction, I'll get her to safety?
妙计 但不好 我带她出去吧
Good idea, but wrong. I'll get her to safety.
- 我知道怎么走  - 我有枪
- I know the layout.  - I have a gun.
你带她出去 我来分散他们注意
You get her to safety, I'll create the distraction.
- 妙计  - 我需要你的手机
- Good idea.  - I need your phone.
- 什么?  - 我要用到手机 拿来
- What?  - I'm doing a phone thing. Come on.
去吧 神探Harry(70年代经典警察电影)
Do your thing, dirty Harry.
没电了 检查下 确认外面没特警部队
Lights out in here. Check it out. Make sure SWAT is not outside.
我们出去看下
Let's check this out.
她逃不了的
She's not going anywhere.
- 别靠近前面窗口  - 看到外面有人吗?
- Stay clear of the front windows.  - Do you see anybody outside?
有人在这里面 我们去看看
There's somebody in the building. We gotta move.
下面
Down here.
你们是时候滚蛋了吧
Might be a good time for all of you to leave.
该死
Damn it.
- 我们被发现了  - 我们完成任务了 回来会合
- We got sirens.  - We're all done. Meet us back here.
- Burke探员?  - 嘘! 我会带你离开的
- Agent Burke?  - Shh! I'm getting you out of here.
- 我们在这  - 怎么那么久?
- We're here.  - What took you so long?
比计划晚了30秒 要赶快走了 拿着
We're 30 seconds behind schedule. We have got to move. Take it.
- Peter  - 貌似Diana让特警部队开窍了
- Peter.  - Sounds like Diana knocked some sense into SWAT.
- 我们带Renee离开这吧  - 他们从后门走了
- Let's get Renee out of here.  - They're out back.
- 没关系  - 我要跟着他们
- Doesn't matter.  - I'm going after them.
别跟了 他们有枪 Neal
Let them go. They've got guns. Neal.
该死 他从来不听我的
Damn it. He never listens to me.
- Jones 帮我叫Walker来 我要和他谈谈  - 他已经在这了
- Jones, get me Walker. I wanna talk to him.  - He's already here.
噢 我听说银行的事了 还觉得我能给你省点事
Oh, I heard what happened at the bank. I thought I could save you some trouble.
所以你是来自首的吗?
So you're here to confess?
我知道你会给我打电话 因为Caffrey先生肯定有我手机号
I figured you were gonna give me a call, because I'm sure Mr. Caffrey has my cell number.
Arthur 给他们
Arthur?
除了我公司的起诉之外 还有我的不在场证明
You'll find my alibi in there in addition to my company's lawsuit.
起诉?
Lawsuit?
对 毫无依据的骚扰和毁损名誉
Yes, unwarranted harassment, defamation of character.
还有一系列的其它起诉项目...
And, you know, there's a litany of other charges...
我还是不破坏这份惊喜了吧?
But, gee, why spoil the surprise?
慢慢玩你的游戏吧
Enjoy this game you're playing.
- 你不会有好结局的  - 噢 游戏已经结束了
- It won't end well for you.  - Oh, the game is already over.
无论这个"建筑师"是谁 他都已经赢了
This Architect, whoever he is, has already won.
Caffrey先生 再见
Mr. Caffrey.
对了 如果真是我做的话 也会让我做联邦调查局初级探员吗?
Oh, if I did do it, do you think they would make me a junior FBI agent too?
- 哇 多嚣张的王八蛋  - 哼
- Wow, that is one arrogant bastard.  - Heh.
说得没错
That's one way of putting it.
这次棘手了
This is gonna be a problem.
- 录像没用  - 他们在五分钟内搞定了
- Nothing useful on the tapes.  - They were in and out in five minutes.
制造交通阻塞让警察无法及时到达 加上他们完美的撤退策略
Gridlocked the city to kill response time. Plus they had a perfect exit strategy.
Walker操控着每一步 他也想让我们知道
Walker was in control every step of the way. He wants us to know it.
我们也会这样逮到他的 他唯一控制不住的就是自大
And that's how we get him. One thing he can't control is his ego.
他起诉不是因为虚荣
Vanity is not cause for indictment.
你要抓我的时候 我也不敢胆大包天地走进你办公室啊
I wasn't bold enough to walk into your office when you were after me.
- 真想逮住这家伙  - 地狱的恐怖也及不上被惹怒的联邦探员
- I want this guy.  - Hell hath no fury like a Fed scorned.
我们被一个嫌疑犯进行几百万的起诉...
We are facing a multi-million-dollar lawsuit from a suspected thief...
却眼睁睁看着他在光天化日下逍遥法外
who walked away from the crime scene in broad daylight.
- 你是说我们没戏了吗?  - 最好不是
- What, are you saying we're done?  - We better not be.
否则司法部就要砸掉我饭碗 然后赶你回监狱了
Or I can't stop the DOJ from putting me on the bread line and you behind bars.
他们在城里瞎跑的时候 我们在抓贼呢
While they were chasing ghosts around the city, we were right.
没办法 我们没抓到人
Doesn't matter. We didn't catch him.
最终数据
Final tally.
貌似他们偷走了820万
Looks like they got away with 8.2 million.
- 你确定?  - Jones写得清清楚楚
- You sure about that?  - Jones has excellent penmanship.
四个人 每人两个新秀丽箱
Four guys, two samsonites each.
- 你觉得那些箱多大?  - 不知道 16乘13吧
- How big would you say the briefcases are?  - I don't know, 16-by-13.
- 高呢?  - 四或五英寸
- Height?  - Four, 5 inches.
- 纸币面额都是100美元?  - 对
- Denomination of the bills, all Franklins?  - Right.
一叠一百张 每叠大小不超过8英寸
Hundred bills in a pack. Volume of each pack, less than 8 inches.
尺寸对不上
Dimensions don't add up.
那么每个箱子里就有大概96万美金
We're looking at around $960,000 in each case.
- 总数超过650万美金  - 实际总数是820万
- That's over 6.5 million total.  - Final tally was 8.2.
也就是有超过150万美金下落不明
Which means that more than a million and a half is unaccounted for.
似乎足够分成了
Sounds like enough to be a share.
- 谢谢  - 没关系
- Thank you.  - Sure.
谢谢你抽空见我们
I appreciate your taking the time.
你说有个推测
You said you had a theory.
那些戴面罩的家伙好像漏了些东西
Our faceless friends may have left something behind.
我想重新检查保险库 以防万一
I'd like to re-examine the vault, just in case.
没有好好休息下吗?
No rest for the weary, huh?
被那些疯子用枪指着脑袋 等你们抓到人 我才能安心休息
Those creeps held a gun to my head. I'll rest when you catch them.
这个团伙作案很周密 你觉得他们漏掉了什么?
The team was pretty thorough. What is it you think that they missed?
- 213  - 什么?
- Two-thirteen.  - Excuse me?
保险箱213 我很确定还没人查过
Deposit box 213. Pretty sure no one's looked in there yet.
貌似值得一看
It sounds like it's worth a shot.
噢 抱歉 那是我们其中一个客户的资产
Uh, I'm sorry. That's the property of one of our customers.
- 你需要他的授权或者搜查令  - 这是行长给的
- You'd need his authorization or a warrant.  - Got this from the bank president.
但这个保险箱不是你们客户的
But the box doesn't belong to one of your customers.
- 是你的  - 哈 哈
- It belongs to you.  - Ha, ha.
我想你搞错了吧
I'm afraid you're mistaken.
没有 我们调查了这个保险库的所有箱子
No, we did a background check on all the boxes in this vault.
你知道213这个箱子两个月前租给你叔叔了吗?
Did you know 213 was rented to your uncle two months ago?
- 我觉得这没问题啊  - 有问题
- I don't see why that would be a problem.  - I do.
他两年前去世了 要么这是个奇迹...
He died two years ago. Either it's a miracle...
- 要么就是你伪造了他的申请  - 我打赌是后者
- Or you forged his application.  - My money's on the latter.
好吧 那你们还是看一下吧
Okay, fine. Uh, why don't you have a look?
哇
Wow.
150万现金
One and a half million dollars in cash.
好
All right.
- 你知道她有枪吗?  - 不知道
- Did you know she had a gun?  - I did not.
听着 拿那个袋子 把钱装进袋子里
Okay, get the bag. Put the money in the bag.
计划不错
Not a bad plan.
Walker给你分成
Walker leaves your cut.
你只要等事态平息后消失就可以了
All you have to do is walk out once the dust settles.
- 我认为是天衣无缝的计划  - 被我们发现就不是了
- Pretty good plan, I'd say.  - Except we figured it out.
- 你真觉得自己能逃过联邦调查局吗?  - 你的档案记录可是一场长跑 不是冲刺
- You really think you can outrun the FBI?  - Your record is a marathon, not a sprint.
- 他迟早会知道的  - 闭嘴 把钱装到袋子里
- He'd know.  - Stop talking and put the money in the bag.
你在监控录像里的演技不错
That was a pretty nice acting job you did for the cameras.
- 堪称完美计划  - 闭嘴
- Even the best laid plans.  - Shut up.
Walker说服你帮他 对吧?
Walker convinced you to help him, didn't he?
他说服我没必要等20年拿普通的退休金
He convinced me I shouldn't wait 20 years to have a mediocre pension to retire on.
现在就可以拿到三倍的钱 为什么还要等?
Why wait when I can have three times that?
- 因为你会被抓  - 都说了 他迟早会知道
- Because you'll get caught.  - Again, he would know.
不是叫你闭嘴吗?
Did I tell you to stop?
继续装钱
Keep filling the bag.
- 别再那样了 拜托?  - 怎么了?
- Could you stop doing that, please?  - What?
- 唠唠叨叨 揭人家痛处 真矫情  - 好吧 确实是
- Rubbing it in. It's very hypocritical.  - Well, it's not untrue.
- 喂  - 你知道吗?
- Hey. - Okay, you know what?
- 我厌倦这样了  - 厌倦做人质?
- I'm tired of this.  - Being held hostage?
- 厌倦和你吵架  - 我也是
- Bickering with you.  - You're not the only one.
- 真的吗?  - 真的
- Really?  - Yeah, really.
哇 好吧 我们断绝合作关系吧
Wow. Okay, maybe it is time for this partnership to end.
好啊 我没问题 终于可以不用管你的破事了
Okay, that's fine by me. I can finally start my novel.
- 我的破事? 你连一张违规罚单都不会写  - 知道吗? 你真是...
- Novel? You can barely write a parking ticket.  -  You know? That's very...
- 喂!  - 等等
- Hey!  - Hold on.
- 你真的要绝交吗?  - 你呢?
- You really want this to end?  - Do you?
- 我时刻准备着  - 绝就绝
- I'm ready.  - Let's do it.
闭嘴!
Shut up!
噢 我的眼睛
Oh, my eyes.
这里 我们在这里
In here. We're in here.
- 就在那 给她带上手铐  - 噢!
- Right there. Handcuff her.  - Oh!
- 给她念念她的权利  - 好的 长官
- Somebody read her rights.  - Yes, Sir.
- 干得好  - 你也不差
- Nice job.  - Not so bad yourself.
Walker先生 这个是给你的
Mr. Walker, this just arrived for you.
现在扯平了 你起诉我们 我现在回赠给你
It's only fair. You gave us a heads-up. I'm returning the favor.
- 那我又可以继续起诉了  - 嗯 起诉不了了
- This is going to help my lawsuit.  - Mm. There won't be any lawsuit.
- 为什么?  - 你的内线 Renee供出你来了
- And why is that?  - Your inside woman. Renee talked.
现在赶紧认罪求情吧 要不得坐上25年牢了
Why settle for 25-to-life tomorrow when you can plea-bargain today?
噢 下次别被抓到哦
Oh, next time, don't get caught.
Whitney 打给Arthur 叫律师团
Whitney, call Arthur. Call the legal team.
Neal啊?
Neal?
你准备好了吗?
You ready?
现在准备好了
I am now.
我在公园看到一只知更鸟 然后你说"知更鸟是什么颜色的?"
I saw a mockingbird in the park. Then you say, "What color is the mockingbird?"
我可以用报纸做暗号 但鸟的那个蠢主意就算了
I'm doing the newspaper thing. I'm not doing the stupid bird thing.
- 他状态怎样?  - 好点了
- How's he holding up?  - Better.
- 我看到了以前的Caffrey  - 那就好
- I'm seeing the old Caffrey coming back.  - Good.
无论你扮演的是什么角色 你都做得不错
Whatever part you played in it, you did good.
我知道你叫我来这不单纯是为了表扬我
I'm sure you didn't call me down here to tell me how great I did.
- 不错 你做得不错  - 是很不错 非常不错
- Good. You did good.  - Great. Great.
听着 我知道他不会对我坦诚的 我明白 他可是Neal
Look, I know he won't tell me everything. I get that, he's Neal.
我会盯着他 还有你
I'll keep an eye on him and you.
但那样我只有收拾烂摊子的份 而不是防患于未然
But that puts me in a position to clean up a mess, not stop it before it happens.
所以你想让我来帮你防患
Oh, that's the part you want me to take care of.
告诉我他会不会做蠢事
Just tell me if he's gonna do anything stupid.
- 我不能出卖朋友  - 这是为了保护他
- I can't rat out my friend.  - It's to protect him.
盖世太保和克格勃组织也是这样说的
That's the same rationale that was used by the Gestapo and the KGB.
看着我
Look at me.
他也是我的朋友
He's my friend too.
- 我会考虑的  - 好
- I'll take that under advisement.  - Yeah.
- Mozz  - 我们得谈谈 朋友
- Mozz.  - We gotta talk, my friend.
- 什么?  - 是音乐盒的事
- What?  - About the box.
那个音乐盒出问题了
Something strange is going on with the music box.
是这样的
The trail starts here.
被包裹的音乐盒在你们纽约办公室的取证组存放了两个小时
It was bagged after forensics held it for two hours in your New York office.
- 然后职业督察处要求把它送去华盛顿  - 我就知道他们不会把它留在这儿
- Then OPR requested it be transferred to D.C.  - I knew they wouldn't let it sit still.
就在运送的过程中发生了些事情
Somewhere between here and there, this happened.
这不是原来的音乐盒 只是形状和颜色相似而已
That's not the box. Got a similar shape and coloring.
- 它被换了  - 真的那个已经被带走了
- It was swapped.  - And the real box is in the wind.
虽然我们改变不了风向 但可以调整船帆
Though we cannot change the direction of the wind, we may adjust our sails.
问题是 我们往哪个方向前进?
Well, the question is, which way are we headed?
- 喂?  - Diana吗?
- Yeah?  - Diana.
你准备好参加Fowler的神秘会议了吗? 我在路上了
You ready for Fowler's mystery meeting? I'm on my way.
我随后就到 头儿
I'm right behind you, boss.
--=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: Tracy
翻译: 落寞卷菜% 西皮jo 初见 伊娃
校对: Tracy 影子